Dr. Ye.
Mr. Evans.
I have to say,
I was surprised to hear from you.
I'm glad you remember me.
Of course I remember you.
You were hard to forget.
I'm only here for a week.
For a conference.
Astrophysics.
So, you made it off of that hilltop, huh?
I know about your father.
I did some looking.
I know about your father too.
You run his oil company now.
And Mao is dead, and I'm a professor
at Tsinghua University.
Things change.
Nothing has changed with me.
I'm the same man you met in Shaanxi.
I could've spent
the rest of my life in that hut,
trying to save a subspecies
of the northwestern brown swallow,
or I could use the resources
available to me to do more.
In order to fight power,
sometimes you have to embrace power.
I agree.
And how are you fighting power, exactly?
Why did you write to me?
"In nature,
nothing exists alone."
I did not know who else to talk to.
What would you like to talk about?
Back on that hilltop...
...I did something.
Hey, um, discharge was an hour ago.
So text me if you can't make it, but, um,
I'm ready to go whenever you are.
Oh, hey.
Hey.
I thought you were at Oxford.
Yeah, uh...
I was.
Well, welcome back.
Jack was supposed to pick me up
like an hour ago,
but the bastard
won't even answer his phone.
You okay?
Why are you here?
Stop it. Stop. Stop it now.
I should have stopped him.
Hey. Hey. It wasn't your fault.
It must be the same woman, right?
The one who lit my cigarette?
Maybe she erased herself
from the footage like last time.
Could be her,
could be someone she works with.
Well, find her.
That's what you people do, isn't it?
There's 18 security cameras
in and around your mate's house.
She doesn't show up on any of them.
Strange, isn't it?
Vera Ye recruited
five pet geniuses to Oxford.
Now, Vera and one of her pets are dead.
An invitation. Three circles on it.
And how the fuck do you know about that?
Does it matter?
Isn't that interesting?
They want you to stop work,
and they want you to work for them.
Next week, a meeting
to welcome you to the organization.
I'm going with her.
- No, you're not.
- Yes, I am.
No, you're not.
You were not invited.
You have a choice, Doctor Cheng.
You can go home, mourn your friend,
spend the rest of your life wishing
you'd acted differently the night he died,
or you can help us
catch the cunts who murdered him.
No, no, no, no, no, no, no.
Drink the vodka.
- I'd like those better than the vodka.
- No, drink the vodka.
Drink it for real.
You know, I really tried.
He just wouldn't shut up.
He had to go and pick a fight with her.
Then I was trying to give him a look,
and he wouldn't shut up.
It's okay, Jin.
Who could ever get Jack to shut up?
I think they're real.
Who?
The San-Ti.
I think they're real, and they're coming.
- I know it sounds insane, I...
- It's not insane.
It's the only thing that makes sense.
What they've been doing,
we don't have that technology.
Nobody does.
So, if nobody can do it,
and it's still happening, it's...
I don't know how to fight aliens.
Neither do I, but guess what?
The people that work
for them... aren't aliens.
And I've been fighting people
my whole life.
So have you.
More good news.
We found him.
Panamax oil tanker.
Hasn't delivered oil in 40 years.
Could be 1,000 people living on there.
Got the coordinates.
Mediterranean Sea,
200 miles north of Alexandria.
Do we move?
No.
We wait.
Hola.
Monsieur Evans!
Gabrielle, bonjour.
Mrs. Chiang was telling us
about the San-Ti.
Yes.
Will I live long enough to meet our Lord?
If our Lord wants us to be here
when they arrive,
then they'll make that possible.
They can work miracles.
And if not?
Then that's what's best, isn't it?
Yes.
Sir, our final roster
for tomorrow's summit in London.
- What happened to Rooney?
- He didn't work out.
I see.
- Sir?
- Hmm?
Should we increase security?
What security can we provide
that the Lord can't?
Yes.
My Lord?
We have new comrades
joining us through the game.
For the London summit tomorrow,
we're planning...
They know about the summit.
"They"?
Your enemies.
They know where you are.
They are watching you right now.
Don't be afraid.
Nothing will happen to you.
Not to any of you.
We will protect you.
That's better. It's nice to see you smile.
Fuck's sake.
What's the point of this one again?
- Uh, winning.
- There's a lot of blood.
Yeah, the boss smashed through
my rib cage and snatched my heart.
He's the Heart Snatcher.
Oh, very nice.
- How is the job hunt going?
- I've got a job.
- What?
- I'm an entrepreneur.
That's not a job.
That's a word you learned to pronounce.
Yeah, you think I'm such a loser,
but wait and see.
I don't think you're a loser.
Just think you're lazy.
Yeah. Well, you've slogged your guts out,
and look what you've got to show for it.
"Everything the light touches
is our kingdom."
My job isn't about getting rich.
About protecting people.
Oh, you think that's funny, huh?
Sorry, Dad.
I just don't think the police are heroes.
Well, I'm not police.
Yeah, you're a functionary
for a dysfunctional government.
Who told you that?
It's an original thought, Dad.
I know the po-po discourage those.
Ally said it.
Ally's a twat.
You've been saying that for two years,
but he's still my boyfriend.
So what does that tell you?
That you've got terrible taste in men?
Guess I take after my mum.
When I make my millions
and I buy you a sweet pad,
I'm gonna be like,
"Still think I'm a loser?"
First, you better kill the Heart Snatcher.
Almost had him that time.
Hey.
What do you think?
Yeah, that should be all right.
His mum said it would be a closed coffin.
Do you, uh, think there's anything we need
to get rid of before his family gets here?
Like what?
I don't know. Uh, sex toys, happy pills.
Vintage porn. I mean...
...this is Jack Rooney we're talking about.
I don't think so.
Ah, see?
Told you.
What do you think? It's, uh, handcuffs?
Anal beads?
I do data and equations
and hypotheses and models.
I don't do... this.
I'm not a spy, or whatever you are.
We know where you're heading.
We'll be close by, watching and listening,
making sure you're safe.
Best thing you can do
is avoid conversations altogether.
Don't talk. Listen.
You're there for information,
not confrontation.
The longer you stay, the more we learn.
You go in,
you gather the intelligence, you leave.
No one is the wiser.
Oh, bring a bag.
Clothes, toothpaste...
enough for a few nights.
- Why?
- Just in case.
What? In case of what?
In case you can't go home.
Why wouldn't I be able to go home?
They know
where you live, Dr. Cheng.
When you say "they,"
who are you really talking about?
Do you think
they're in contact with aliens?
You don't need to believe in Santa Claus
to believe people give gifts on Christmas.
Do you believe in Santa Claus?
Ho ho ho.
Hello?
Don't take your phone inside
when you get to the location.
Will you still be able to track me?
I hope you're kidding.
Green light.
"And she looked
at the Big Bad Wolf and said,
'Grandma, what big eyes you've got.'"
We do not understand.
What don't you understand?
- He intends to eat her.
- Yes.
She does not want to be eaten.
No.
So why does she remain in the house
when she knows
the wolf intends to eat her?
Uh, she doesn't know.
The wolf is pretending
to be the grandmother.
We do not understand.
Well, he's dressed like the grandmother.
He's wearing her clothes.
He looks like her. He sounds like her.
But he is not the grandmother.
He is the wolf.
Yes, but, uh, Little Red Riding Hood
doesn't know that.
The Wolf has communicated with her?
He has.
If he wanted to achieve
his aim of eating her,
why did he communicate with her?
After he communicated with her,
and she learned his intentions,
why didn't she run?
Uh, because she didn't learn
his intentions.
He was hiding them from her.
Don't you ever hide your intentions?
We do not understand.
Well, for instance, the, um, you know...
these pests who are tracking us,
they're trying to hide their intentions
because, well, otherwise,
they couldn't get to us.
Pests?
Our enemies.
The intelligence operatives
you warned me about.
Pests are destructive insects
or other animals that attack
crops, food, and livestock.
Your enemies are human.
Yes.
Yes, well, uh, you see, well...
What I was doing there, I was, um...
I was using a metaphor.
I was describing them as pests
because, well, that's what they are.
Annoying, inconsequential,
easy to eliminate.
Like bugs you can squash under your shoe.
Can't you ever say anything
that you know to be false?
Can't you lie?
What is known is communicated
as soon as communication takes place.
So, you communicate through thought?
While we are still like barnyard animals,
squawking at each other.
You do this? You lie?
Well, I... I try not to, but, um...
Yeah.
Yeah, we all do sometimes.
One way or another.
And the wolf, he is also lying?
Yeah. Yeah, I suppose he is.
We would like to speak to him.
What?
Is he still in the grandmother's house?
Where is that?
Uh, in the forest.
Which forest?
There are many forests on your world.
Oh no.
No, no, no. It's not...
It's... It's not real.
We do not understand.
Well, it's a story.
You know, the wolf, the grandmother,
the, well, Little Red Riding Hood.
None of them exist.
So the story,
it is a lie about a liar?
Yeah.
Yeah, I suppose it is.
We need to consider this.
My Lord?
We think we understand now.
Ah.
See, that's, um...
That's why you need us, my Lord.
We can help you.
Help you understand us better.
A liar is someone whose words are false.
A liar cannot be trusted.
We cannot coexist with liars.
My Lord...
Uh...
My Lord?
We are afraid of you.
My Lord...
My Lord, are you there?
My Lord?
Welcome, Dr. Cheng.
Where exactly are we going?
To the summit.
What's happening at the summit?
Don't worry.
Our Lord'll take care of us all.
"Our Lord"?
Jin!
I'm glad you made it.
I am too.
I'm so sorry about your friend.
- I didn't think you'd come.
- I know that voice.
- If I missed this meeting...
- I met her at the graveyard.
She's known about us all along.
- And that surprises you?
- So, what made you come?
I want to know
why the universe works the way it does.
I want the big answers.
If anyone knows those answers,
it's our Lord.
Yes.
I trust in our Lord to provide them.
I know it feels strange
to say it at first.
It makes us all sound
like religious loons.
Except our Lord is real.
You haven't had anyone protecting you
since the flood took your family away.
Now you do.
This has been my family
since I was a little girl.
It's an honor to be part of the family.
I know someone
who'll be very happy to hear that.
Our founder is coming.
How did Evans get off that boat
without us seeing him?
How did that girl scrub herself
from the security cameras?
- Everyone, if I could...
- Do we move on 'em?
No, let's listen.
He might admit to something.
It's wonderful to see all your faces,
old and new.
It's a very special night
for us all to be here.
The rumors are true,
so I'll get out of your way.
I am honored to introduce
the founder of our movement,
our reason for hope,
the cause of our salvation.
Everyone, please welcome our founder...
...Dr. Ye Wenjie!
Welcome.
I knew you'd come.
There's been nothing
connecting her to this since the funeral.
Nothing we've seen or heard.
But they've been controlling
what we see and hear.
So how come
they're letting us hear this?
Thank you.
When I was a young woman,
I saw my country torn apart.
My family was destroyed.
I was sent to hell.
I saw human beings
cut each other to pieces,
destroy each other without a thought,
all in the name of progress.
And what has changed?
We continue to destroy each other
and the world around us.
We cannot save ourselves.
But we are not alone.
Four light-years away,
the San-Ti have achieved miracles
beyond our wildest imagination,
in spite of the chaos
that plagues their world.
And now, they are coming
to share their knowledge with us,
to teach us how to survive and to thrive.
They travel to us at enormous speeds,
but it will take them centuries to arrive.
Four hundred years.
Four hundred years?
Space is big.
...in history falls to us
and to our children,
and to their children after them.
We must prepare the world
for their arrival
and prepare our descendants
to welcome them.
I believe all our guests have arrived.
I thank you.
My partner in this movement,
Mike Evans, thanks you.
And our Lord, the San-Ti, thanks you.
We will give them the gift of our world,
so that they can do with it
what we could not,
so that they can mend
what we have brok...
Down on the ground!
Move!
Get down!
Stop!
Do not resist.
If this is happening,
it is our Lord's will.
Please.
Sit down.
Our Lord will protect us
from our enemies.
Hey.
Come on. Let's get you out.
Come on. Come on.
There you go.
How are you doing?
We're gonna take you somewhere safe.
Your friend Auggie too.
Just till we get a handle on this.
You got lucky. I'm a terrible shot.
Hello?
Hey.
I... I just wanted to check in
and see how you were doing.
Yeah, I'm...
okay.
So, I was thinking, after Jack's funeral,
we could maybe all use a bit of a break.
Um, I've... I've rented
this little cottage on the beach
down by Seven Sisters.
So, I mean, I don't know if you feel
like staring at the Channel but...
That sounds nice.
I'll invite Saul and Auggie.
And Raj, of course.
Maybe it should just be us chickens.
He's back at base anyway.
Auggie could make us her famous palomas.
We could drink them on the beach.
They say you can see France
on a clear day.
Hmm.
Are you driving somewhere?
Uh, yeah.
Where?
I don't know exactly.
Somewhere safe.
What's going on?
Nothing. I'm... I'm okay. I promise.
Jin, where are you?
I'll... I'll come and get you.
I have to tell you something.
Something fucking insane but true.
Jin, what's happening?
Just listen, okay?
It's about all of us.
It's about you and me and Jack.
All of us.
It started a long time ago.
Before we were born.
What do you think?
It's like seeing an old friend.
Clear the helipad. Clear the helipad.
Incoming.
Clear the helipad immediately.
All right. Watch your step.
Yeah. Here, sir.
Watch your step.
It's gonna be different this time.
Our own research base.
Why here?
No borders. No politics.
No interference.
Our transmission center.
It took me eight years
to receive a response last time.
We might have to wait.
They've been trying to reach you
this whole time.
What?
Ever since they got your message.
You left the base
before they could reply again.
You're very important to them.
They're curious to learn more about us,
and they want to teach us
about themselves.
It was so long ago.
Sometimes I wondered if it was real.
It's real.
They're coming.
You have brought us hope.
We know about the ship.
What's on Judgment Day?
Why is it so important?
If you're as clumsy as you were
at our meeting, you'll never find out.
- We have you, don't we?
- And why do you think that is?
You've got me because they let you.
Well, judging by the number
of casualties on your side,
I wouldn't say you let us do anything.
We didn't let you.
They let you.
You have no idea what they can do.
You think you do, but you don't.
They are coming.
And there's nothing
you can do to stop them.
And when they arrive...
you'll be so grateful.