(HUMMING)
♪ I'm trading my home for the road again
♪ Singing my songs with an old best friend
♪ Running around with a child's mind... ♪
Whoo!
♪ ...A man gets lucky
just a couple of times. ♪
Sing it, Hester.
(BOTH HUM THE MELODY)
Hm.
- You're excited!
- Damn right I am.
Finally got a lead on Iorek.
He might not be the same bear.
The Iorek I knew...
- Some crazy seal-hunter...
- (FLAMES ROAR)
...got him drunk,
tricked him out of his armour.
An armoured bear is nothing
without his armour.
Hester!
I'm right here.
What do you see?
Looks like we're not the only ones
heading to Trollesund.
Lee, are you sure Iorek
will want us making trouble?
That bear saved our lives, Hester.
We owe him trouble.
Hey!
This is an oil port.
There's no smoking on the quay.
Then I nearly made a horrible mistake.
Lee Scoresby, aeronaut for hire.
Tell me, who are all these people here?
My question exactly.
New arrivals arouse suspicion.
I did hear a rumour that interested me.
Rumour of a bear.
Any truth to that?
Yes, I heard a rumour, too,
of an aeronaut
who creates bedlam wherever he goes.
Any truth to that?
- (SIGHS) Here we go again.
- Friendly place.
Yeah.
No, it's not.
Can we just stay out of trouble?
Gyptians.
Never seen them so far north.
FARDER: The spy-fly will have reached
Mrs Coulter by now.
Our business here must be in haste.
JOHN: I don't like it here either.
Go see the witches' consul,
get whatever help you can,
and we leave here as fast as possible.
It's been 40 years since
I saw Serafina last.
She might not like what she sees.
I remember you as a younger man, Coram.
You weren't much to look at even then.
(BOTH CHUCKLE)
You're sure you should take the girl?
Something tells me I'll need her.
PAN: Quite something, all this.
My whole life I've wanted to be here,
and now that I'm here,
I'm not so sure I want to be.
FARDER: Lyra!
Lyra.
A word, please.
I need to know if I can trust in
your readings of the alethiometer.
How do you decipher it?
I kind of feel them or see them.
It's like... like going down
a ladder at night.
(SHOUTING)
You put your foot down,
and there's another rung.
Well, I put my mind down,
and there's another meaning.
I sort of... sense what they mean.
It's got a trick in it.
- Sort of like focusing your eyes.
- Ah.
So, say you wanted to ask
the alethiometer
what your parents are doing now?
- Well, the Madonna is Mrs Coulter.
- Oh.
The Madonna, is it?
And for Asriel,
it would be the globe.
So, I think of my parents
when I put the hand there.
And then I go for the ant,
because that means busy.
But how do you know
what these meanings are? Hmm?
The Magisterium. Put it away, Lyra.
You understand the man
we're going to see is important?
Yes.
The Witch Consul is a link between
the human world and the witches.
He will decide whether
to pass our message on.
And we need the witches.
Yes, but he'll want to know everything.
The Consul is the only way
to contact the witches,
and he must trust us first,
but if he does,
a witch called Serafina Pekkala
will surely come to our aid.
With her help,
we will find the children.
- You mean she'll lead us to Roger?
- Yes.
Just follow my lead.
Keep that thing hidden, OK?
(KNOCK ON DOOR)
How can I help you, Farder Coram?
I met a witch some years ago
in the fen country of eastern Anglia.
Her name was Serafina Pekkala.
I wish to get a message to her.
I'm aware of your relationship
with Serafina Pekkala, Farder Coram.
I represent a number of Gyptian families
who have lost children.
We believe there is an organisation
that is capturing these children,
ours and others,
and taking them north.
We need her help to get them free.
Well...
You realise that relations
between the witches
and the authorities
are... perfectly cordial.
It is my job to keep them that way.
You refer... to the Magisterium. Hmm?
This fight is not ours.
They are stealing children.
This is war for all of us.
And I know Serafina
will want to be part of it.
The children do not remain here for long.
They are taken some distance inland.
Do you know what happens
to them there?
I've heard variously
of the Maystadt Process,
or an... intercision.
The process is shrouded in secrecy,
but the rumours are disturbing.
There's a reason why you don't see a child
on the streets of Trollesund.
We, too, have felt the effects
of missing children.
Then I will leave you to let Serafina
know what we ask of her.
Come.
I understand you are in possession
of an alethiometer.
I have eyes everywhere
in Trollesund.
Yes.
May I look at it?
It's exquisite.
Do you possess the books of readings?
Actually...
...I can read it.
You are very wise to say so.
How?
I just can.
Well...
I wonder if I might ask to see you do so.
Down here,
there are many sprigs of cloud-pine.
Which one belongs to
Serafina Pekkala?
I can summon the witches
through cloud-pine.
Each spray of cloud-pine
is specific to a witch.
(MECHANISM CLICKS)
Show us - which one is
Serafina Pekkala's?
Chameleon...
...and the moon.
This one's hers.
I'd like to give you something
to take away with you.
Carry this spray with you,
and if you ever truly need her...
...she will come.
Dr Lanselius,
may I ask you something?
Of course.
What question should we be asking you
that we are not?
You're weak.
You may have heart,
but the Magisterium have muscle.
I would ask where I could obtain the
services of an armoured bear.
I understood the armoured bears
answered to nobody.
There is at least one who does.
An exile.
He shamed his people,
but be warned -
his skill with metal
makes him useful to the town.
They don't like strangers knowing about
him or interfering in his affairs.
You'll find him beside Einarsson's Bar.
But to get him away will take some doing.
His name...
...is Iorek Byrnison.
Iorek Byrnison!
(LOW GROWLING)
Iorek Byrnison,
can we talk with you?
We wish to offer you employment.
- I am employed.
- We need fighters,
or in all probability, we will.
We're going north till we find the place
where children are being kept captive.
When we find them,
there will surely be a battle.
(LOW GROWLING)
What do you do... in the metalworks?
I mend the broken machinery.
I lift heavy objects.
And what kind of work is that
for a panserbjørn?
(FIERCE GROWL)
If you'll excuse me saying,
Iorek Byrnison...
...you could be living
free and proud on the ice,
hunting seal and walrus,
or going to war,
winning great prizes.
(LOW GROWL)
I know the people you are seeking.
The child-cutters.
People of this town,
they pretend not to see,
but I see.
- And are you a coward like they are?
- (GROWLS)
A coward?
(GROWLS)
(SNARLS)
(GASPING BREATHS)
We need you.
I am not for sale.
It's quiet today.
- Big hearing in the Consistorial Court.
- Oh, is that right?
And I thought it was because
everyone knew that I was coming.
- We didn't announce it.
- No, I know.
Trying to be funny.
My apologies.
(MRS COULTER LAUGHS)
They do like to look at me, though,
as I pass.
Well... you've acquired a reputation.
A reputation for stirring up trouble.
Now quickly.
The cardinal will not be kept waiting.
I thought I was perfectly clear.
You were.
Try to keep your head down.
Show some restraint.
No, you express it all most eloquently.
Yet, not a few days later,
you invaded a college
protected by scholastic sanctuary,
and undermining
a centuries-old relationship.
Yes.
It was very unfortunate.
(DOOR OPENS)
It's good to see you again, Marisa.
It has been some time.
Not so long.
Can I get anything for you?
I know how much you like your sustenances.
(LAUGHS)
Food, tea, water?
I arrived fed and watered.
Just skip to the part where you reveal
what punishment you intend for me, hmm?
Punishment?
Such a strange word.
I don't intend to punish you.
(LAUGHS) I'm sure that's not true.
I fear our project
has become too noisy.
I am passing leadership
of the Oblation Board
on to Father MacPhail,
and, as of now,
you are stripped of all official duties.
- Hmm...
- Hmm?
- Beautifully done.
- Hmm.
Now, should I tell you
why you won't,
and why I go north tomorrow?
I have Lord Asriel.
You have Asriel?
In a jail...
...controlled by bears,
who are, in this case...
...controlled by me.
I will travel to the North,
and I will give him to you
as an act of service...
...and, in return,
you'd allow me to pursue our project
until its end.
And you will allow me
to ask one question
of Fra Pavel...
...and his alethiometer.
That seems like a high price.
For Asriel, it's cheap.
Now, shall we sit...
...and discuss how to proceed?
Please.
FARDER: Lyra, the way you
spoke to that bear,
he could have torn your throat out.
And you could've imprisoned me
and sold me back to Mrs Coulter.
I know who to trust, Farder Coram.
But if you're wrong,
you could do yourself damage.
I'd do myself... more damage
not trusting anyone.
What happened between
you and Serafina?
We loved each other.
You loved a witch?
We had a child.
A son.
There was an epidemic.
There was nothing we could do.
He died.
And she wanted to rip the world apart...
...fly to Yambe-Akka,
fight her...
...if that's what it
took to get him back.
I wanted to mourn in peace.
Haven't seen her since...
(TEARFULLY)...after we buried my boy.
I'm so sorry, Farder Coram.
It was a long time ago.
Say what you like about the North,
wherever you go is guaranteed
to be a bar full of men
who should be at home but aren't.
Any gentlemen in the mood
for a game of hazard?
No?
How about a game of flippity-flop?
It's real simple.
There are three pots.
A flip pot, flop pot and a game pot.
As long as you can stake a pot,
you can play.
Will you join me in a glass of hot rum?
My round.
I'm just looking for some conversation,
you see.
What are you all afraid of?
That I'll learn your secrets?
That I'm... grubbing for shady business?
I'm not.
I am simply after a bear.
It's kind of royal-looking,
fancy armour.
I know. Strange for these parts.
You know what a bear looks like,
don't you?
Thick coat, big teeth, cute little nose.
Right.
Well, at this point,
you're either being ignorant
or wilfully obstructive.
(YELLS)
What are you thinking?!
(GASPS)
You started the fight,
- now you're losing the fight!
- I know what you're going to say.
(YELLS)
Come on, up!
Lee, your turn! Do something!
(GRUNTS)
OK, you gotta kick.
That's right, kick again!
Bottle!
(GLASS SMASHES)
That was nice! Love it! More of that!
No!
Hey! You almost got me!
(GRUNTS)
Nice kick!
All right, we're having fun now.
Come on!
- (BLOWS THUD)
- Hey, Lee!
You got this!
What are you doing, going high?
You can't go high.
They're going to get you!
- Whoa!
- Hold him!
- (GASPS)
- Throw him out!
Quit asking about bears, Aeronaut.
Well, that showed them.
I'd like to think I made my point.
And what point was that?
Three watches and a wallet.
I've wanted to visit this room
for quite some time.
He's normally very careful
of who he allows up.
You understand anything you ask me
may take weeks of study.
I want a guarantee that,
whatever you find out,
I'll be the first to know.
What is your question?
It's a simple one.
Who is Lyra Belacqua?
- Surely, you of all...
- Just ask the question, Fra Pavel.
LEE: Has anyone seen a bear?
LYRA: What do you want with a bear?
You're bleeding.
Hazard of the job.
And what job do you do?
I'm in aeronautics.
- What part of being an aeronaut...?
- Let me give you a tip, kid.
Never upset a seagull.
You're not serious.
Not if I can help it.
Will he want to see you, this bear?
I hope so.
You know where he is, don't you?
- The town's no place for Iorek.
- How do you know him?
Well, she's just a sprung box, isn't she?
She just keeps asking questions.
Lee Scoresby.
Can you tell me where to find him?
I'm just following her lead.
What is it about him?
What's keeping him trapped?
Kid, I'll tell you that when you tell me
what you know.
Another time.
Why won't you tell me?
Because we need him,
and I'm not sure that
you won't take him from us.
FARDER: Serafina once told me
of a prophecy about a child.
I think it could be Lyra.
People see something in her.
You should have seen Dr Lanselius.
The look on his face when
she answered his questions.
- He looked...
- How?
Greedy.
Greedy?
There are things going on, John,
that we do not understand.
The further north we go,
the more we must watch her.
(SHRILL SCREECHING)
Ah.
- A spy.
- No.
The Witch Consul must have
passed on our message.
Serafina's daemon.
So it's true.
The witches do have the power
to send their daemons from them.
I have... changed much
since last you saw me, Kaisa.
You have, Coram van Texel.
May I introduce John Faa,
king of the western Gyptians?
This is Kaisa,
daemon of Serafina Pekkala,
queen of the Lake Enara clan.
Serafina sends you happiness...
How far away is she?
...and she asks if you have come
to make war.
If it takes war...
...to get our children back,
then we are ready to wage it.
- I'd hope the witches would help.
- Not all will.
Some clans are working with
the Oblation Board.
Those who search for Dust.
And where are they now,
these Dust-hunters?
Four days northeast of here.
They call it the Station.
The witches call it Bolvangar.
Bolvangar?
Translated, that means...
...fields of evil.
Can you take us there?
Serafina Pekkala will support you
in whatever route your path takes.
LYRA: What do you think it is, Pan,
makes it look like that?
I don't know,
but it's... It's amazing.
Do you think that's what
Dust looks like?
There's something in it.
Not quite...
It looks like a city.
It's gone.
Maybe it's the alethiometer,
telling us where to go,
where Roger is.
Maybe.
Do you think he's cold?
I hope not.
I'm the same.
I find myself thinking about Billy
at the strangest times.
Even found myself thinking about him
on the toilet this morning.
Heard you met a bear.
Yeah.
Fun?
Scary?
Confusing.
Definitely not what I expected.
We're going to get them back, Tony.
I know.
We will do whatever it takes
to get them back.
HESTER: Hey, Lee, can we take a break?
We've been searching for hours.
I don't think he's here...
Iorek Byrnison!
Uh...
It's been some time.
What are you doing here?
IOREK: It hasn't been some time.
It's been three years. (GROWLS)
Three years, long as all that?
It has not been a good three years.
(GROWLS)
We want to help, Iorek.
Can we help?
I owe you. We both know it.
And how can you help me?
Some look good naked. You do not.
Who has it?
Your armour?
I am drunk, Lee,
and not behaving as a bear should,
and I'd rather you leave me.
And what if I don't want to go?
You know, when I see an old friend,
I'm inclined to tell him where I've been,
adventures I've had.
I have done things...
...I can't talk about.
I've done some things I'm not too keen
on people knowing either.
Tell me what you've done.
We wouldn't judge you,
couldn't judge you.
And what if I desire to be judged?
Don't let him go.
We came here just for you, Iorek!
Then you should leave, Lee,
for I neither asked you to come,
nor do I want you to stay.
It's not often we get
customers waiting for us.
You haven't got that lucky,
Mr Sysselman.
I'm not handing myself in.
Oh, is that right?
(BOTH LAUGH)
How can I help?
I'm representing the bear.
The bear's case is closed.
Correction, I am representing
myself via the bear.
The trouble is, you confiscated
my property instead of his.
Yes, I doubt that, Mr Scoresby.
This is why I've been seeking him.
Now, this is a bill of sale stating that
I, not Iorek Byrnison,
own his armour.
He lost it to me in a game of cards,
you see.
I've come back to reclaim it.
The bear's armour belongs
to the Magisterium.
Ah, yes.
He is paying off a blood debt.
Ha. Well, yes,
this document is correct
as far as the Crime And Debt Act,
chapter 3, paragraph 4.5
is concerned. The trouble is,
the Crime And Debt Act is superseded
in this circumstance by
the Possession Of Goods Act,
part 3, subsection 4,
Miscellaneous Provisions,
which clearly states, and I quote,
"The possession of valuables
- "belongs to..."
- Please!
Do not doubt my intelligence, Mr Scoresby.
It's not your intelligence I doubt,
Mr Sysselman.
Who paid you to write this
and how much will it cost me
for you to rewrite it?
Now, you be careful what
you accuse me of.
Not even money'll work.
They've got you well controlled,
haven't they?
Whatever you're accusing me of...
Now, the North, as I understand it,
has always been a place for people
who didn't fit in or didn't want to.
The Magisterium has been
trying to gain power
out here for a generation.
No-one ever actually let them in
until, perhaps, now.
Be very careful.
He's a bear.
He can't be a slave.
Not to you,
the Magisterium or anyone.
Shame on you, Mr Sysselman.
MRS COULTER: I believe I have been helpful
in the disposal of Iorek Byrnison
and helping you take your rightful throne.
I'm perfectly prepared.
My Northern king...
We're leaving?
Yes. The witches have agreed to help us.
But... but we haven't got Iorek.
The Witch Consul said we need Iorek.
He also warned there was little chance
of getting him away.
You don't know what awaits us out there.
With Iorek on our side,
we stand a chance.
Lyra, we've just had a good word
that your father
has been taken prisoner
and is guarded by armoured bears.
The Magisterium are everywhere.
We can't dare wait.
They have Asriel?
They do.
Then all the more reason to have
an armoured bear on our side!
We don't want him.
We made enquiries.
Iorek is being punished for fighting
and wrecking this town. He was drunk.
That's the only reason they managed
to prise his armour from him.
He is a savage.
Lyra, that is not necessary!
Let her do it.
(MECHANISM CLICKS)
The alethiometer says that they got
him drunk and tricked him.
No bear would normally drink spirits.
JOHN: He tore through the police house
and the bank.
The only reason they didn't shoot him
was because of his skills with metal.
Why don't you check your alethiometer
to see whether
I'm telling the truth now?
You don't need to,
because you know it.
I choose who I fight alongside,
and that is my final word.
I heard you had a visitor.
What did Mrs Coulter want with you?
You think I can tell you that?
It's more than my position is worth.
Come now, Ratty.
You mistake me for someone
who cares about your position.
Remember...
...I know what kind of man you are.
Your filthy predilections.
And the trouble they've caused.
You shouldn't do this to me.
Hmm.
I need an answer...
...from the alethiometer.
I wish to know
what Grumman discovered.
That is a dissident.
That is heretical.
It's my job to understand heretics,
is it not?
Then ask the cardinal for his permission
before demanding...
I'm not asking the cardinal.
I'm asking you, Ratty.
How can I get what
Grumman discovered?
You have neither his permission
nor Father MacPhail's.
I don't need his permission!
I just need your consent!
Will you deny it?
Or must I expose you...
...to the world?
Because I will...
...out of spite...
...if I don't get my own way.
I rethought it.
The question I want to ask -
how can I find
what Grumman discovered?
(PAVEL GRUNTS)
(PASSING VOICES)
Good.
Send me word as soon
as you have something.
- (WATER SPLASHES)
- You know what, Lyra?
There is one person in this town
who knows that bear.
Pan, you're a genius!
Hey, can you remind me
why we're here again?
It's the only place in town with a bed
and a halfway decent plate of scran.
It worries me that bacon is more important
to you than survival.
And by the way, you are aware
everyone is looking at us?
- It's time to leave.
- Yeah, we're not leaving without Iorek.
Thank you.
They know you stole from them, Lee.
Every minute we spend here
- longer than we should...
- That bear saved my life, Hester.
And we came here to repay him,
and he told us
- he didn't need our help.
- Who didn't need your help?
You know, kid, much as I like you,
now is not the time.
I representJohn Faa,
ruler of the western Gyptians,
and we would like to hire you.
You can't afford me.
Mr Scoresby, the Magisterium
is stealing children.
We have to get them back,
and it occurred to us
that the help of an aeronaut
might be of some use.
We'd be grateful for your services.
We pay in gold.
I know what you're fighting, kid.
You're going to lose.
Do you play cards?
(LAUGHS) What do you know about cards?
I used to play them
with the scholars where I lived.
They were much cleverer than me,
but I generally won.
I learned that sometimes a bad hand
can be your greatest weapon.
Sometimes, when there is no hope,
it can allow you to bluff magnificently.
Remind me never to play cards
with you.
We need you... and the bear.
You need the bear, and I'm secondary.
How do we get him to come with us?
I know you know.
He's obliged to this town.
Iorek's going nowhere.
He's an armoured bear.
What could they...?
They got his armour.
Hey, you got there without
needing my help.
Why's his armour so important?
War is the sea he swims in
and the air he breathes.
No.
Without his armour...
His armour means as much to him
as Hester here does to me.
His armour's like his daemon?
His soul is in those pieces of metal.
But the Magisterium
will have it well hidden.
Now, I've been thinking that maybe
I'm outgunned in this town,
but I've got some craft of my own,
you understand.
No, if I can't win Iorek's freedom,
then...
Where did she go?
She's quick
and she stole my bacon.
PAN: Lyra, assuming this works,
which is a long shot,
you've still got to convince Lord Faa.
Just leave that to me.
Lyra, this way.
Through here.
(METAL CLANGS)
(HEAVY THUDS)
(GROWLING)
(LOW GROWLING)
(CLATTERING)
I know where your armour is,
Iorek Byrnison.
Or at least I know how to find it.
How could you know where it is?
I...
I don't understand.
Why don't you just make some more armour
out of this metal here?
It's worthless!
My armour is made of sky-iron,
and it was made for me... by me.
I have spent months looking for it.
(GROWLS)
How have you found it?
This.
It tells me the truth,
and I'll use it if you come with us.
I will come with you,
but I have a right to take vengeance.
If they try to stop me taking my armour...
...they die.
That seems fair.
But only if they try and hurt you.
Good. Where is my armour?
(MECHANISM CLICKS)
It's hidden.
The Magisterium have it hidden.
It's in the cellar of the oratory.
(ROARS)
PAN: This is not good!
(THUMPING AND CLATTERING)
He's going to tear everything apart!
(IOREK ROARS)
We've got to stop him!
(PANICKED SHOUTING)
LYRA: Iorek! Stop!
(ROARING AND CLATTERING)
(GASPS)
Iorek!
(ROARS FEROCIOUSLY)
(LOW GROWLING)
Clear the square!
Move!
All right, then, boys.
(SHOUTING)
(ROARING)
(SCREAMS)
(GROWLING)
Level them!
Fire!
(BULLETS RICOCHET)
Reload!
(ROARS)
Reload immediately!
(SCREAMS)
LYRA: Stop! Stop!
- Stop!
- (ROARS)
Let go of him!
I told you - if they fight...
- ...they die!
- You owe me a debt.
Now you can repay it.
Do as I ask - don't fight these men!
You owe her a debt, too? Damn, Iorek,
you're racking up debts faster than me.
Heard there was some action occurring.
I thought I'd come see what's going on.
Hello again, Mr Sysselman.
Having fun? I hope so.
(GROANS)
Just turn around.
Walk away with me.
Please.
LEE: She's just a kid,
but she talks some sense.
These people need our help, Iorek.
Let's go give it.
This isn't who you are.
(REVERBERATING ROAR)
(SIGHS)
We're packed up.
We're really going.
Lyra, trust me when I tell you,
it's within us to beat these people.
Course it is,
but would you mind if I brought
along a little extra help all the same?
- How did you...?
- He's been mistreated and tricked,
just like the Gyptians have been,
always mistreated and tricked.
He's practically Gyptian.
- Just like I am.
- Lyra...
You cannot constantly be
disobeying me.
I agree.
Who wants a disobedient kid?
But she's right.
He's a good bear.
You won't have any trouble
as long as you pay him.
And me.
And who's this?
You told me he'd asked for me.
No, I told you he'd be grateful for you.
I was working on him already
being grateful. You've entirely
- messed up my sales pitch.
- What did I tell you
about how I play cards?
Lee Scoresby.
I can fight and I can fly.
I don't come cheap,
and neither should I.
You'll get gold for gold.
And you are going to need
all the help you can get.
He's an aeronaut. He has his own balloon.
He could be useful.
Well, then,
welcome aboard, Lee Scoresby.
We have a long and dangerous
journey ahead.
Iofur?
(CLATTERING)
Iofur.
I appreciate the need to keep
our meeting a secret,
but it will be difficult
if I can't see you.
Don't waste my time!
No, no, of course.
You... You are right.
You are a king,
and I am impertinent.
I am a king,
and you are not a queen.
And we are very grateful
for your help in capturing Asriel.
Many have tried,
and only you have succeeded.
And yet I...
Yet you doubt me.
King Raknison,
I was a great help in aiding you
in the disposal of Iorek Byrnison
and helping you take your throne.
And I agreed to capture Asriel
to repay my debt.
But he is now my prisoner
in my dungeon,
and I will do with him as I choose.
Well, perhaps, then...
...as an envoy from my people...
...I could offer you something that
might be of worth to you.
And in return, you may permit me
to oversee how you deal with Asriel...
I am a king! I have all I need.
I'm talking...
...of a baptism.
(GROWLS)
Acceptance into the Magisterium.
Baptism?
King Iofur...
...you are a great bear...
...and the Magisterium would be stronger
for having you part of it.
Part of us.
Will you walk the path with us?
No bears have ever been brought
into the Magisterium before.
You would be the first bear
to be baptised...
...and the only.
But do not mistake me,
the honour would be ours.
In return for which,
I will give them Asriel?
No, you will keep him here,
but you will ensure
his laboratory is destroyed
and that his research into Dust
is erased.
But I will control him.
(GROWLS SOFTLY)
I'm simply asking for you
to show your loyalty to us
so that we may show
our loyalty to you.
In the meantime,
I'm sure you have much to attend to.
How soon can this happen?
The wheels have already
started turning.
Asriel will be controlled.