(DISTANT SHOUTING)
(GROWLS)
(WHISPERS) Sal!
SAL: How did you get here?
Are you two safe?
PAN: Good questions for later.
For now, we pretend
we don't know each other.
It's very good to see him again.
He said the same about you.
But he's different, Lyra.
And so's Salcilia.
They've hurt him?
No. But clearly
he's been through a lot.
Well, he's alive,
and that's all that matters.
After we found Billy,
I thought that maybe Roger...
I thought that, too.
(DOOR BANGS OPEN)
(DOOR CLOSES)
Bridget McGinn!
Could you come with me,
please, Bridget?
I haven't had my dinner yet.
Come on, don't make a fuss.
Quick, quick.
(DOOR CLOSES)
Straight ahead.
(DOOR CREAKS)
Come on.
Reactors activated.
Intercision primed.
(GRINDING)
(CLICKS FINGERS)
MAN: Right. We want to take
some measurements.
But I was measured when I got here.
Ah, those were just your vitals.
These are slightly more sophisticated.
Could you stand
on the metal plate there...
(MACHINERY THRUMS)
...and stare at the green light?
All right. Now turn yourself to the left.
And now to the right.
LYRA: What are you looking for?
We'll take those pictures again,
just to be safe.
What are you taking pictures of?
You're measuring Dust, aren't you?
Can you see Dust in these pictures?
Who told you about Dust?
One of the other girls.
No, they didn't. Where are you from?
And you see, Doctor, the thing is
that I wash regularly.
You won't find any Dust on me.
(LAUGHS)
Well, it's perhaps a little more
complicated than you might think.
What happens to the children
that leave this place?
Where do they go?
To a place for more grown-up children,
of course.
So... they don't die?
You don't cut their daemons away?
Lizzie, this is a philosophical
establishment,
not a child chophouse.
Now, may I take my picture?
Good.
Now keep perfectly still.
(ALARM BLARES)
(SHOUTS) Oh, for crying out loud!
Can we not fix this?
Please make your way to
the first available fire exit.
Don't forget your shoes, Lizzie.
(ALARM CONTINUES)
This always happens
after someone's been taken.
Form an orderly queue. Come along.
(ALARM CONTINUES)
Follow the others. Out you go.
No running.
- Lawrence Kirby?
- Here, miss.
- Annie Padia?
Roger Parslow?
Here, miss.
- Esther Manville?
- Here, miss.
- Barclay Carter?
- Martha Farewell?
- Here, miss.
- Tommy Lindsay?
- Lizzie Brooks?
- Here, miss.
ROGER: Lizzie?
Joseph Blakely?
When I saw you,
I couldn't believe it. I just...
Billy Costa was here
and then they took him,
and he hasn't been back.
- There's help coming, Roger.
- Help?
- The Gyptians are coming.
- The Gyptians will be destroyed!
They'll never make it.
They need our help.
We need to find a way out.
We need an escape route.
Lyra, this requires careful thought.
Those that get caught breaking the rules,
they don't last long.
We can't stick out.
- Shane Walter?
- Here, miss.
- Beth Reid?
Lyra, don't!
- Imogen Gould?
- Here, miss.
Oops.
You never could listen.
Sticking out is the only way
we're getting out,
and I am not staying here.
- Otis Lavell?
- Agh!
Children!
SISTER CLARA: Order...
- ANNIE: Who did that?
- ...or there will be consequences.
- Children, please, we're... Oh!
- (CHILDREN GIGGLE)
SISTER BETTY: Who did that?
SISTER CLARA: Order!
(SHOUTING)
Which is the way out?
There's an area they don't allow us to go.
If I was a guessing person,
I'd guess that's the closest thing
this place has to an exit.
LYRA: Wait.
Someone's coming.
(FAINT PATTERING)
LYRA: What's that sound?
(PATTERING CONTINUES)
There's something inside.
These are daemons without humans.
ROGER: David.
(DULL THUDDING)
Shay.
Bridget.
These daemons belong to the children
who've been taken and not come back.
(THUDDING CONTINUES)
That's Billy.
His daemon's gone.
That means...
I'm sorry, Roger.
You knew?
I found him.
Before he died.
He got out of here somehow.
I helped him find his ma.
Lyra...
...if the daemons are alive,
where are the children?
(ALARM CONTINUES)
CHILDREN:...Seven, eight, nine, ten.
One, two, three...
- ROGER: Was Billy like this?
- LYRA: Yes.
We can't end up here.
(ALARM STOPS)
ROGER: The alarm's stopped.
We have to get back.
Lyra!
(FOOTSTEPS RECEDE)
(WIND HOWLS)
(NURSE GIVES ORDERS)
Pass the word around...
about what's happening here.
They've got to be ready to escape
when we give them the signal.
And they've got to keep it
a deadly secret. Do you understand?
The fire alarm.
Next time it sounds, it'll be me.
Get everyone ready to leave.
- Are we drinking?
- (CHUCKLES)
(DRINK POURS)
Here's to freedom
and the conclusion of our work here.
Rumour is, she's on her way.
- When?
- Her airship was seen
in Trollesund last week.
Ever since the breakout
of that idiot Gyptian child,
she's been itching to get back here.
Well, we've the new severing equipment
to show her,
if we were to focus on that.
We are on the edge
of magnificent discovery -
that is the line we need to reinforce.
She mustn't be allowed to
focus on the mistakes.
Do you think we are...
...on the edge of discovery?
- You doubt it?
- There are times when I worry...
Well, when I'm concerned, perhaps.
This is just pain we're causing.
How many more children have to die
before we get it right?
We are doing what is necessary.
We get this right and we will truly
free generations from tyranny of sin,
and the Magisterium will recognise
and celebrate us
for the job we've done here.
And if we don't?
We can and must succeed.
(FAINT SOBBING)
(SOBBING CONTINUES)
REPORTER: And leading the expedition
to Alaska, we have Colonel John Parry.
What will you be taking with you
from home?
JOHN: Oh, if I could,
I'd take everything from home.
Just pick it all up and put it
in the back of the backpack.
But I can't do that,
so, um, some photos,
a small plastic jar of Marmite...
a little of that goes a long way...
and a toy car of my son's.
I haven't actually told him that yet
so, sorry, Will.
Have you been able to explain to him
what you're about to do?
Well, yeah. Actually, it's been easier to
explain it to him than Elaine, my wife.
I think helping scientists drill
for ice sounds kind of cool to a kid.
Not that he's going to be
able to remember it,
but I'll be writing, keeping them updated,
Shackleton-style.
(LAUGHS)
I'm going to write
some truly epic letters,
keep it, you know,
kind of romantic.
REPORTER: Well, that sounds ever so sweet,
Colonel Parry...
(REPORT FADES)
Why aren't you going in?
She knows we're watching.
That's enough for now.
I'll find an opportunity
soon enough.
(AIRSHIP THRUMS)
(DISTANT THRUMMING)
ANNIE: Is it her?
ROSE: It's her!
I can see the golden monkey.
Rose, check all the beds.
The next child she takes
is going to be from the boys' dormitory,
and we're going to be sure of it.
We cannot stick out.
Martha, listen by the door.
Tell us when she's close.
- You've been making advances?
- Mm-hm, yes.
Since you were last here,
five have survived,
mostly due to the new separator.
It's much more sophisticated
than the previous model,
and so has a much better survival rate.
Now the patient can be conscious
during treatment,
and they remain conscious after.
It's quite something.
And are they responsive
after treatment?
We can't make a judgment on that
at present,
but initial indications do suggest...
- They're getting more responsive.
- An exciting development.
May I see it in action?
- Let's set something up.
- Wonderful.
Hmm.
LYRA: I need your help.
- With what?
- She can't find me here.
- You know her, don't you?
- I've come here to save you.
When I leave, you're coming, too.
All of you.
This place is guarded by wolves
and Tartars.
You get past them,
you've just got a wasteland of ice.
There's people coming to save us -
the Gyptians.
- They will help us. Trust me.
- I trust nobody in this place.
She's my mother.
(MUFFLED GASPS)
And I know what she's doing.
She's severing kids from their daemons.
Severing?
That's what happens?
Yes.
If she finds me here, Annie,
I don't know what she'll do.
I need you hide me. Please.
Under the bed.
When I say so, pull yourself up
and you don't let go.
You understand?
- She's on the corridor. She's coming now.
- Positions!
(GASPS)
Hello, girls.
What did I miss?
Empty bed?
Bridget and Lesley were
sent for testing.
They haven't come back yet.
Hmm.
You know, I do care for you
so very much.
It lifts my heart to find you
in such good spirits.
Seeing your bright, shiny faces makes me
a very happy woman.
Well, girls,
you've kept yourselves perfectly.
Not that I expected anything less.
(GASPS)
(GIRLS GASP)
Well done.
- (DOOR SLAMS)
- (GASPS)
- Steady!
- We've got to hurry!
All right.
Let's move it!
- Steady!
- Mind the ropes!
- All right, steady.
- Steady!
ALL: And two and three!
(ALL HEAVE)
(THEY SHOUT)
Come on!
Hang on!
(WHISPERS) We break out of here.
There's miles and miles of ice out there.
We'll freeze.
It's either that or staying here
and being severed from your daemon.
When the time comes,
I will sound the fire alarm.
Get everyone together in their snowsuits
and be ready.
For what?
To fight.
- (DOOR BANGS OPEN)
- Lizzie Brooks.
Lizzie Brooks, can you come with me?
Get her daemon!
(PAN SQUEALS)
(LYRA CRIES OUT)
No, you don't.
Thank you.
I'm only doing what's necessary,
right?
Pick her up.
- Please, no!
- (SCREAMS) Pan!
Lizzie, Lizzie!
Calm down.
LYRA: Let go of me!
Get her inside.
- It doesn't hurt.
- You don't know who I am!
- It just feel like a loss.
- Let go of me!
- Come on.
(LYRA SCREAMS)
- No!
- Lizzie, calm down. Calm down.
(SCREAMS) Let me out!
- Reactors activated.
- Let me out!
Let me out! Let me out!
Intercision primed.
Let go of me, let go of me!
Mrs Coulter won't want this!
(MACHINE THRUMS)
PAN: Do something, Lyra!
Let go of me!
Get that door shut. We don't want to fritz
the anbaromagnetic system now, do we?
I am the daughter of Mrs Coulter,
and she won't want this!
You're doing something great.
You're part of something great,
try to focus on that.
How did she know Mrs Coulter's name?
Shouldn't we listen to her?
She knows her!
Mrs Coulter! Mrs Coulter!
- I thought you had this under control.
- LYRA: Mrs Coulter!
Mrs Coulter!
Mother!
- Mother!
- (WHISPERS) Lyra.
(SCREAMS) Mother!
- (MACHINERY POWERS DOWN)
- Lyra!
Free them.
Drink this.
Can't say it'll cure anything, but it'll
certainly make you feel better.
Infusion of camomile -
that's what my mother fed me
when I'd been upset.
And it worked... most of the time.
I was quite the emotional child,
by all accounts.
It was a surprise to me,
what you said in there.
Who told you what I was to you?
Well, you know now.
And I can answer all your questions
if you have any questions...
I do.
Here.
If I was trying to drug you,
there are many other means to do so
other than a drink.
The camomile will
make you feel better.
Good.
I can guess the first question.
And the answer is that I...
...I didn't keep you...
...because it wouldn't have been good
for either of us.
And Asriel had ideas
about what was best,
so I let him pursue those ideas,
but it wasn't because I didn't care.
I just wasn't equipped at the time.
Lyra...
...I never meant to harm you.
You must have been able to see that.
No harm?
Then what are you doing here?
Nothing to you.
No-one's going to harm you, Lyra.
No-one's ever going to hurt you.
You have my word on that.
They were about to cut Pan from me.
Out of me.
Because they didn't know who you are.
And I saved you.
It's Dust.
- You're after Dust.
- Shh.
Dust is not a good thing.
Grown-ups are infected so deeply
that it's too late for them...
...condemned to a life of sin,
guilt and regret.
This is for a better future,
a better life.
A life without Pan would not be
Your daemons are wonderful
companions and friends to you
when you're young,
but at the age that we call puberty...
...an age you'll come into very soon,
darling,
daemons bring all sorts of
troublesome thoughts and feelings.
And that's what lets Dust in.
A little operation before that
and you're never troubled again.
If it was so good,
you should have let them do it.
You should have been glad.
(SIGHS)
Every boundary in experimental theology
requires the sacrifice of the few
for the many.
Once we've ironed out the teething
problems, this will change the world.
Until then, that equipment
is not suitable for you.
But others?
Billy Costa?
Roger?
If they're friends of yours,
I guarantee you they will not get hurt.
Billy Costa is dead.
Well, that is unfortunate.
Well, I will find those people
responsible.
That's you!
Lyra, I need you to understand
that I have taken on
this extraordinarily hard job
for the benefit of all.
This is what I can give.
This is my calling.
And I am sorry if me being who I am
has done you damage.
One day, you'll see all I've done
to right this world for you.
I'm sorry.
I never meant to do you harm.
What shall we do now?
Well, I could take you back to your dorm.
You could stay here.
I'd like that.
You would?
Lyra...
..I can't tell you how happy I am
to have found you again.
And I can't tell you how happy I am
to be found.
Lyra, dear, I believe
the master ofJordan College
gave you something
before you left his care.
Isn't that right?
Alethiometer?
The trouble is, I believe
the only reason he gave it to you
was because he wanted it to fall
into Lord Asriel's hands.
And if there's one thing
that man doesn't need,
it's more toys to do damage with.
I know he told you
not to tell me about it.
And I know you're not the sort
to break your word.
But now is the time
to choose a side.
Now is the time to choose
who you belong to...
...once and for all.
You saved me.
He didn't.
And you're my mother.
I am your mother.
I kept it safe.
What a funny old tin.
You have been careful, haven't you?
It's soldered.
- (SCREAMS)
- (MONKEY SCREECHES)
(SCREAMS)
(BOTH SCREAM)
Lyra! That's enough.
(SCREAMS)
(ALARM BLARES)
What's that now?
Another of your bloody tests?
Nothing was planned by me.
Not while she's here!
That's my signal!
You're safe.
Those kids we saw, Roger,
you need to free them.
What if they don't want to come?
- They don't seem like...
- You can persuade them.
What will you do?
What I'm best at - cause some chaos.
(ALARM CONTINUES)
Faster, Lyra. We haven't the time!
We get to that intercision room
and we destroy that machine.
Come on!
(DOOR OPENS)
Take those off, Lizzie.
You don't need those.
We're getting out of here.
You should, too.
No, no. You will soon be back
in your room,
which is good, because this is
the best place you could possibly be.
What's his name,
the daemon she cut from you?
Nicolas.
I loved him so much.
Now do you see what she's done to you?
To all of us?
Nicolas...
(ALARM CONTINUES)
CHILDREN:...Eight, nine, ten...
One, two, three, four, five...
I need you all to come with me.
We're getting out of here.
Why aren't you coming?
I know they've separated you all
from your daemons,
but you've still got a choice -
do something...
...or do nothing.
Do something, and we can make them
pay for what they did to you.
Do nothing,
and all your daemons will know
is that hurt of that final moment.
Is that really what you want?
We've got to stop this
happening again.
PAN: The doctor said if you leave
the doors open,
the system gets fritzed, right?
LYRA: So let's fritz it.
What are you doing?
I'm pressing every button I can
until something happens.
(MACHINERY THRUMS)
(METAL CREAKS)
(CRACKING)
That thing sounds like it's going to blow.
Come on, Lyra, we have to go!
(GRINDING)
(GRINDING STOPS)
(DEEP RUMBLING)
(DISTANT SHOUTING)
(THUD)
Round up the children.
Wait for me, and make sure you have
them all, you understand?
(ALL SHOUT)
- Come on!
- Let us out!
Stop! All right, children,
let's not get excited now.
Let's not get silly.
Let's just do as we're told, sh-shall we?
(THEY GASP AND GRUNT)
Tell me, do you remember Billy Costa?
It wasn't my fault.
I was just obeying orders.
- He was only a boy!
- (BLOW LANDS)
We've come to rescue you.
(CHILDREN SQUEAL)
Come on, girls. We aren't here
to hurt you. You're safe.
(LYRA SCREAMS)
(GUARD SHOUTS)
(GUARD YELLS)
(SHOUTS)
(FEROCIOUS GROWLING)
What took you so long?
It's good to see you, too, Lyra.
We need to get the other children
out of here.
Let's go.
You're welcome. (ROARS)
(GROWLING AND SNARLING)
(MEN GRUNT AND GASP)
(LYRA GASPS)
LEE: Is that all you've got?
(GROWLING AND SNARLING)
(GUARDS SHOUT)
(YELLING AND SCREAMING)
Take that child.
She's the one with value!
We just need the children alive.
Kill everyone else!
(COMMOTION STOPS)
It was Billy who showed us
we could all get out.
Get free from this place.
Go.
But there's so much to do.
You didn't come to the North
just for this, Lyra.
My father.
I need to free him.
Go well.
- Is this the balloon driver?
- I'm an aeronaut, kid. Lee Scoresby.
- And this is...?
- This is Iorek.
- This is Iorek?
- Hmm. Yeah.
He just doesn't look like
how I imagined him.
You were hoping for better-looking?
Weren't we all?
We need to take to the skies.
You all right with heights, Roger?
- Not really.
- You'll learn to be.
Balloon driver!
Let's go!
I thought you might need a tow.
Well, thank you, Miss Pekkala.
Always good to see you in the skies,
Mr Scoresby.
Your daemon is examining me.
Well, it's been a while
since we've seen you.
LEE: That was quite a performance earlier.
Thank you.
Question - what can
we expect going forward
in the sense of mayhem and chaos?
There may be fighting,
but you've fought before.
And gladly.
But as the situation
grows more complicated,
so my situation grows
more... complicated.
The child is destined
to be important -
to create and resolve conflict.
So this is about her.
She matters more than
she can ever know.
The fate of more than this world
depends on her.
Well, I had a contract
with the Gyptians
over what was accomplished
in Bolvangar.
This... This seems like
a whole new thing,
which requires, if I'm honest,
new contracts and new payments...
She will need you, Lee.
You know, a man should have a choice
whether to take up arms or not.
And you need her.
That's not how I expected
this conversation to go.
Is it not?
No, I was hoping you would find a way of
chucking me some danger money.
Instead, you blindsided me with...
...love.
Good.
The polar star will guide you
to Asriel.
The wind is strong.
You're a capable navigator.
So it's me. She's responsible
for the fate of everything,
and I'm responsible...
...for her?
The world is in your hands,
Mr Scoresby...
...and I am delighted it is.
- Impressive.
- Yep.
And they want you
on their team?
Shut up, Hester.
FARDER CORAM: Poor little things.
Can't even speak any more.
TONY COSTA: That's it. This way.
FARDER CORAM: Cages loaded. Ready to go.
Move out.
I can't help worrying about
what happens when we get them home.
What do you mean?
We'll return them to their parents.
And if they don't take them?
Even those that love them
may be frightened
to see them so... different.
Those that they don't take back
will come join us as Gyptians.
You did well.
Well?
We all fought them, at least.
We did better than fight them.
We defeated them.
Billy won't be the last child they hurt,
but we made it much harder for 'em.
I thought we'd be bringing him home,
Maggie.
He'd be so proud of us.
The way we helped the other children.
Helped Lyra.
She's a fighter, that one.
Reminds me of someone I know.
(THUNDER RUMBLES)
(GENTLE THUD)
(CLICKING)
(CLICKING INTENSIFIES)
(CREAKING)
(GUN COCKS)
(GENTLE THUD)
(SCREECHING)
(IOREK ROARS)
Cliff-ghasts!
(CLIFF-GHAST SCREECHES)
(CLIFF-GHAST YELPS)
Cliff-ghasts.
I hate cliff-ghasts.
Hold tight. A little turbulence.
- Iorek, see any more out there?
- No. It's clear.
Your shooting must have improved, Lee.
(SCREECHES)
- (GUNSHOTS)
- (YOWLING)
(CREAKING)
(CREAKING INTENSIFIES)
(CLIFF-GHAST SHRIEKS)
(LYRA GASPS)
- (SCREAMS)
- ROGER: Lyra!
(SCREAMS) Lee!
- (SCREAMS)
- Lyra, hold on! I'm coming to get you!
LYRA: Lee!
- Get her, Lee!
- Hold on!
- (SCREAMS)
- Lyra, take my hand!
(GASPS)
(SCREAMS)
(SHOUTS) Lyra!