(ROARS)
(WHIMPERS)
You didn't leave?
Why aren't you at the airfield
with the others?
The others are leaving?
Why?
This is the best place
we could possibly be.
They cut out your daemon, not your brain.
You seem...
...upset.
The girl's gas balloon -
did you see which way it went?
There were a lot of girls
at this facility...
Lyra.
Did you see which way Lyra went?
I don't know a Lyra... Mrs Coulter.
Then you are no use to me.
I'd like... to be of use.
I would like to make you happy.
Happy?
Here?
Yes.
This is the best place
you could possibly be.
(SISTER CLARA CHOKES)
(GASPS)
(SISTER CLARA GASPS)
No... Shh-shh-shh...
I didn't mean it, I didn't mean it,
I didn't mean it.
I don't know where to go.
(SISTER CLARA WHIMPERS)
Hm.
(PAN WHIMPERS)
PAN: Lyra.
(LYRA GROANS)
(PANTS)
(GROANS)
(ECHOING) Iorek!
- (ECHOING) Lee!
- (FAINT SCREECHING)
PAN: Shush. Those cliff-ghast creatures
might still be around.
- (FAINT SCREECHING)
- (GASPS)
- (FAINT GROWLING)
- Iorek.
(FAINT GROWLING)
(THUDDING)
(GROWLING)
(ROARS)
(THUDDING)
- (DOOR CLANGS SHUT)
- No!
- (BANGS ON DOOR)
Lyra, check the alethiometer.
Ask it if anyone's coming to rescue us.
Where is Iorek Byrnison?
He saw where we fell.
He saw the bear tracks.
And he's headed this way.
He's coming to rescue us.
And I wish I was a witch.
That way you could fly off
and see if my father is here.
(SQUEAKS)
But you are not a witch.
You're a little girl.
Who are you?
(CHAINS RATTLE)
(SIGHS) Jotham Santelia.
Regius Professor of Cosmology
at the University of Gloucester.
You're a scholar?
And you...?
What's your name?
Lyra.
Lyra Belacqua.
(CHUCKLES)
I don't suppose you've seen...
...my father?
Asriel Belacqua.
He was taken prisoner by the bears.
It wasn't too long ago
he was sitting where you are now.
(CHUCKLES)
- He was here?
- (CHUCKLING) Yes.
But the rogue cheated his way
to Iofur's side.
(CHUCKLES) Word is,
he's persuaded your father
to let him return to his laboratory
on the highest of mountains.
But make no mistake -
that laboratory is still a prison.
And King Iofur will never let Asriel
leave that place.
He will die up there
conducting his heretical experiments!
- (CHUCKLES)
- Me and Iorek Byrnison will save him.
You're not getting out of here!
And Iorek Byrnison
will certainly not save you.
Why not?
Because there are 200 bears here.
They'll kill him with fire-hurlers
before he even gets close
and then set upon the corpse
like he's a seal or a walrus.
Iorek should have been king
but was disgraced and exiled.
He will never be allowed
back in the palace.
Hatred is a powerful motor,
and King Iofur hates every inch of Iorek.
You're stuck here, as am I.
Till you wilt.
Or they break you!
(LAUGHS)
(DISTANT GROWLING)
I once heard that what Iofur wants most
is to be human.
It's why he hired me.
My downfall came
when I told him he was a bear
and will always be one.
But unless you are a witch
and can magic him a daemon,
you will fail to please him,
just as I have.
I need to speak to Iofur Raknison!
- It's about Iorek Byrnison!
- (BANGS ON DOOR)
(GROWLING)
There's something I know
that the king needs to know!
(CHUCKLES) Just like your father.
(CHUCKLES)
Protecting your own skin, are you?
(LAUGHS)
Betraying your friend.
- Try and stay hidden.
- PAN: I will.
- BEAR: What do you want?
- (DOOR CLANGS)
(GROWLS)
JOHN PARRY: It's been easier to explain it
to him than to Elaine, my wife.
I think...helping scientists
drill for ice
sounds kind of cool
to a kid.
Not that he is going to be able
to remember any of it. But I'll be writing,
keeping them all updated,
Shackleton style.
I'm going to write them some...
some truly epic, er... letters.
(BREATHES QUICKLY)
(LOW GROWL)
Who is this child?
Greetings to you, great king.
Why do you disturb me?
I've got something very important
and secret to tell you.
It's about Iorek Byrnison.
Iorek!
Come closer.
Come.
(GROWLING)
Well?
I am his daemon.
But you're just a human.
Humans get animals.
It makes sense for bears to get humans,
doesn't it?
Bears, leave!
Iorek Byrnison was the first bear to get
a daemon, but it should have been you.
I would have much rather been your daemon.
How has a bear got a daemon?
And how are you far away from him?
I'm like a witch's daemon.
I...
I can travel.
And we stay connected.
As for how he got me...
It was at Bolvangar.
Mrs Coulter probably didn't tell you
everything they were doing there.
Child-cutting.
And all kinds of other things too.
Including making artificial daemons.
Even for bears.
Daemons?
For bears?!
Mrs Coulter didn't give me
a daemon.
I imprisoned Asriel for her. (GROWLS)
I want to be with you.
That's why I'm here.
To tell you there is a way
for me to be your daemon.
What way...
...is that?
Iorek's coming for you now.
My bears will kill him
before he even gets close.
Thinks he can challenge you
for the throne,
but what he doesn't know is that if you
were to beat him, in single combat...
...his strength would flow into you
and we would be united as one.
Why should I believe you?
I can prove it.
I can prove what I am.
Ask me something that only
a daemon would be able to find out.
If you're lying to me...
...I will feed you to Iorek myself.
Tell me...
...the first creature I killed.
I will have to go to a room by myself
to do this.
(SNARLS) Whatever you have to do,
you can do it in here!
When I am your daemon
I will show you how I do it.
- (SNARLS)
- Until then...
...I will die before I show my secrets.
(GROWLS)
Over there.
(PANTS)
Come on, come on, come on.
Where is Iorek now?
And how am I supposed
to tell him what I've done?
Trust him.
Who was the first creature you've killed?
(WHIRRING)
Well?
I beg your pardon, Iofur Raknison.
I didn't know you were so...
...great and powerful.
You're playing for time.
The first creature you killed
was your own father.
(GROWLS QUIETLY)
I think you're a new god.
Only a god would have had the strength
and power to do such a thing.
Mrs Coulter deceived me.
LYRA: She deceived all of us.
Now do you see why you need me?
You're scared.
That the other bears won't understand.
Tell them you called
Iorek here yourself.
Tell them that the winner
will rule over the bears for ever.
Make it your idea.
Not his.
Make it my idea?
Yes.
And the fools will believe me.
Great king...
Now it's time for me to leave you.
Leave me?
Iorek approaches. I can feel him.
He must not know what he's fighting for,
or else it will make him
too passionate and...
He can't see that I'm loyal to you.
No. You must stay here with me, daemon.
If you make me, I will stay.
But give me a chance to prove my love.
Very well.
Ready me for battle!
(KNOCK ON DOOR)
Charles Latrom.
I was back in Oxford again.
I thought we could have a chat, Elaine.
No, thank you.
Elaine...
I'm sure you've guessed already.
I wasn't in Oxford by chance.
I have urgent information
about your husband.
And I can't say it to you on your porch.
Where's your lounge?
What a pleasant room.
It's strange.
Some houses you walk into
and you know they're not happy places.
Other houses, it could be a smell
or something indescribable,
but you know a happy family lives inside.
You know nothing about this family.
I know you have a son.
Will.
Stay away from him.
I've no intention
of going anywhere near him.
I'm on your side, Elaine.
Who do you work for?
When I left the Marines, I was offered
the opportunity to do some...
...some intelligence work.
So, MI5, MI6?
Maybe we don't need
to answer that question.
- Tell me what you know aboutJohn.
- We're concerned.
We believe that before he disappeared
he was entangled in something nasty.
I'm sorry?
We're investigating the disappearance
13 years ago
of some rather valuable objects.
Dangerous objects.
And your husband's name
keeps getting brought up.
What objects?
What if I told you there was
a possibility, albeit slight,
that we might,
with the right information,
be able to find John himself?
I have already buried my husband.
I'm not talking about his corpse.
And if our information is correct...
...he could be alive.
There is no chance of that.
And I'm telling you...
...there is.
I can't help you. I know nothing.
He wrote to you.
He wrote every day.
Those letters could have
vital clues in them.
My husband left me with nothing.
I have nothing for you.
That's not true.
He didn't leave you with nothing.
You get money every month
from a bank account that he controls.
I'm not helping you.
I'm at liberty to search this place,
with or without your consent.
Do you have a warrant?
- I can get one.
- Well, we'll wait for that, then.
Otherwise I will call the police
and they can sort this out.
Are you aware that if you are obscuring
evidence from Her Majesty's Government...
I've seen no evidence that you work
- for Her Majesty's Government.
- ...that you're at risk ofjail time...
- Can I see some ID?
- ...and your son could end up in care.
Do you know what you're risking here?
I'm frightened of everything.
Being frightened of you
is just one more thing.
(GASPS)
What...? What the hell's that?
What?
Snake. A snake.
There was nothing of the kind.
I know what I saw.
It's your mind playing tricks on you.
Fine.
I'll leave you be.
But I will come back with...
...as you say...
...the right paperwork.
We can get him back
for you.
You have every reason
to cooperate with us.
(DOOR OPENS)
(DOOR SHUTS)
(WAILS)
How was she?
Not good, then.
Do you ever think that people just
don't understand what's good for them?
What do you want me to do?
I don't care how you do it.
I want the letters.
(THUDDING)
Lyra! Are you OK? What is it?
- Tell me, child.
- I've done a terrible thing.
I told Iofur to fight you in single
combat, and he's going to kill you.
I tricked him
so he wouldn't just kill you at the gates.
You tricked him?
I thought I was doing the right thing.
You were.
I need to fight him,
to end his tyranny.
I can't lose you.
You won't, Lyra.
He's not the real king.
He doesn't even act like one.
You do.
Show him he's nothing.
IOFUR: Your king... awaits you!
My bears!
Iorek Byrnison has come back!
At my invitation.
I drew him back.
And I will destroy him.
I've come here
to give you a real fight, Iofur.
You are no king!
And I will show you that.
(ROARS)
(LYRA CRIES OUT)
(GROANS)
Iorek!
Look at him. That's no king.
Whimpering pup!
I will place his head above my palace!
I'm so sorry.
I'm sorry.
And his memory shall be obliterated!
Why are you helping him?
Liar!
You're no daemon!
(SNARLING)
(SCREECH)
(SILENCE)
(GROWLS QUIETLY)
You're hurt.
You're badly hurt.
You tricked a bear.
He wasn't a bear.
You showed me that.
There's a man in your dungeons.
Will you free him?
Yes. I will.
You helped me get my kingdom back.
You're one of us now, Lyra,
and I will give you a new name.
You're no longer Lyra Belacqua,
but Lyra Silvertongue.
Lyra Silvertongue.
Now...
...the bloodmoss.
Mum? Again?
You've got to stop doing this.
They were here, they were here. They came.
There was a man with a snake.
- What?
- He said he was secret service,
but he wanted...
I know he wanted stuff about your dad.
And I wasn't going to just...
Hey, OK, not here, please.
Your dad, I think he was involved
in something dangerous.
Dangerous?
And it's... It's still happening.
Whatever he started, it's still happening.
Mum, you're scaring me.
And now they think he's still alive.
They think Dad's alive?
Hey, Mum, look at me.
(DISTANT VOICES AND LAUGHTER)
OK, OK. Not here, OK?
Let's get you home.
IOREK: Bears!
There will be no more killing.
This is the end of death in this palace.
And it is time for a new beginning.
Bear ways,
not human.
Up ahead.
Go on.
Roger?
Roger!
Lyra!
Iorek Byrnison made me stay out
in the cold while he came to rescue you.
We fell out of the balloon together.
I don't know what happened to Lee,
but he was still airborne
when I last saw him.
Lyra,
I need you to use your symbol-reader.
Tell me my friend Lee is safe.
(COGS CLICK)
He crashed with his balloon,
but he seems safe.
A man with nine lives. Ha!
And the Magisterium?
Iofur was their puppet.
They're coming here.
Trying to.
My mother's with them.
We need to get out of here.
Once she knows Iofur is dead,
who knows what she might to do?
Iorek, the alethiometer.
My father will need it.
We'll need the truth to defeat her.
I need to give it to him.
I need your help to get to him.
And we will go with you.
Yes. We will.
(ROARS)
(CHATTER)
What on earth is going on?
Iofur Raknison is dead.
Asriel is free.
They're sending everyone north.
You'll be coming too.
Father MacPhail.
Our paths do keep crossing.
You're to travel home.
The Cardinal wishes to speak to you.
You failed.
Your project lies in ruins,
all your experiments have yielded nothing.
I'm here for Asriel.
Asriel?
Asriel is with Iofur.
- I made sure that he...
- Yes. I remember your reassurances,
but Iofur gave him
the freedom to experiment all he wished.
He had his own custom-built laboratory.
It seems you had less control
than you thought.
And now Iofur is dead.
What?
When?
The bears that were his guards
are now his protectors.
The Magisterium needs him stopped
once and for all.
You're quite terrified of him, aren't you?
Why?
(STAMP TO ATTENTION)
Do you think that he is ahead of you?
Do you think he understands Dust
in a way that you don't?
I think you promised to control him
and you haven't.
Well, MacPhail, I need to come with you.
Have you not listened
to anything I've said?
- You've already endangered enough...
- I know him.
You know I do.
I can smell his next move.
And I know Dust.
I've studied it.
I'll be able to understand
what he's doing, what he's done.
Please, don't deny the Magisterium
my help.
I seek only devotion to the Magisterium.
The Magisterium has my devotion.
You do understand what I'm saying?
Lord Asriel needs to die.
Hm.
(FAINT CLATTERING)
(DOOR LOCKS CLICK)
Mum...
W... W...
Mum, stay where you are.
They could still be here.
That man... I knew he would...
Come on.
Mum, we're going now.
- I was right.
- Not now, Mum. Come on.
They have been watching us.
They want the letters.
Come on, Mum.
Will, stop. You have to believe me!
I need you to believe me.
I know my head isn't right,
but you have to believe me.
I believe those letters are important.
I believe there was a man with a snake.
I believe you, OK?
OK.
OK. Come on.
Will?
My mum needs to come in for a bit.
There's been a break-in at home.
She just needs a place to stay.
- Come in. Let's call the police.
- You can't.
They can't see her like this.
And if they do, they'll take me into care.
Then what are you going to do?
Maybe I just need to go home, tidy up,
then I can bring her back.
I just need to think.
Please.
And your door was always open,
remember?
And now I need it to be open.
Come in, love.
She-She might need to stay overnight.
I've got some spare pyjamas.
We'll be fine.
Mum...
Mr Hanway's a good man.
He'll keep you safe here.
He will keep you safe, OK?
Find them, the letters.
OK. OK, OK.
(DOOR OPENS)
(DOOR SHUTS)
(CLANKING)
(CHEERFUL HUMMING)
I'm not sure I like that song any more.
LEE: I have to sing when I'm nervous,
you know that.
- Think she's bust?
- Of course not. We just need
to get out of here
so someone can take a look at her.
And how do you suppose we do that?
She's our only means of travel!
(WHOOSHING)
Maybe I can be
of assistance.
When did you...?
I didn't... I-I didn't expect...
One of my sisters
managed to track your movements.
You are important to us, Mr Scoresby.
But I failed you.
And her.
I lost Lyra.
You didn't fail me in the slightest.
Or her.
You fought for her.
And now her fate is in another's hands.
She's alive?
And Roger? And Iorek?
Kaisa brings word
that they all live and all thrive.
Iorek, with Lyra's help,
has reclaimed his throne.
Yes!
She is...
Well, isn't that something? Wow!
SERAFINA: I believe this is yours.
Where did you...?
How did...?
Oh.
Oh, this means you need me to fight again,
doesn't it?
The battles are just beginning.
The great war is coming soon.
No-No more fancy talk.
I'm just a hustler. I've played my part.
I was useful for a piece,
but I'm no use to you now.
You're wrong.
And it's Lyra who will need you.
So this is still about fate?
Of course it is.
She needs me?
She needs all of us.
Then I hope I'm strong enough.
(THUDDING)
There. Can you see?
LYRA: That's where my father is?
Why does he want to be here?
That... you will have to ask your father.
(DOOR OPENS)
(DOOR SHUTS)
- Are you sure they've gone?
- (DOOR SHUTS)
(CLATTERING)
(FOOTSTEPS)
(FOOTSTEPS APPROACH)
(BREATHES QUICKLY)
(YELLS)
(CAT MEOWS)
Oh!
(THUD)
(THUDDING)
(WIND HOWLS)
(LYRA GASPS)
If you need me, I will be close.
I will stand down the bears
that are keeping your father prisoner.
His guards are now my guards.
Be safe.
Both of you.
You all right, Lyra?
Last time we saw him, he was your uncle.
We're just giving him his alethiometer.
And then maybe we can... go home.
- This for me or for you?
- Bit of both.
I know you're brave,
but hopefully you know
that if you are ever scared...
...I'm here.
I do.
I do know that.
(KNOCK ON DOOR)
- Lyra.
- Hello, Thorold.
Little Lyra!
Come in, come in.
What are you doing here?
You must be chilled.
I'll get the fire lit.
No!
(SHOUTS) No!
I did not send for you!
You have to leave.
You have to turn around and leave!
I did not send for you!
- I came here to free you.
- No.
No, you have to get out before...
(GROWLS) Asriel.
(GROWLS QUIETLY)
Oh, you didn't come alone.
Who are you?
Roger Parslow, sir.
I work in the kitchens.
AtJordan College.
Thorold, prepare these children
a hot bath and...
...make them some food.
Sir.
Roger Parslow...
...I am very pleased you came.