FATHER MACPHAIL OVER TANNOY:
For each and every one of you...
...going out to fight
this abominable foe...
...in the face of an attack
on e verything we hold sacred...
...I implore you to channel
the Authority
in this time of need.
(STELMARIA GROWLS)
STELMARIA: The aurora is strong now.
And the child's here.
(BREATHES HEAVILY)
STELMARIA: It's time.
I know.
(SNIFFS)
What is all this stuff?
(FAINT CLICKING)
I understand you arrived here
on Iorek Byrnison's back.
New king of the bears.
I believe you preferred the old one?
But you should be happy now you're free.
(CHUCKLES) How does a little girl
acquire the king of the panserbjørne
as a guardian?
It's been quite a journey to get here.
That's not an answer.
And I don't remember inviting you.
You don't want me here?
Left you where you were safe, Lyra,
atJordan College.
Whatever you've brought me...
...I hope it was worth it.
Now, what is it?
I'll tell you...
...if you tell me why you...
...why you lied to me
about being my father.
I would have been so proud.
Why would you have been proud?
Because you're...
...Lord Asriel.
And you're my father.
Your mother, she...
Do you know who your mother is?
Your choice in women
is almost as bad as your choice in bears.
I don't think we should continue
this conversation.
Why not?
Because it is getting sentimental.
Sentimental?!
And because I wouldn't like to.
Are you crying? It's unnecessary.
Lyra Belacqua, you are stronger than that.
It's Silvertongue now.
You don't want my name?
Silvertongue feels like my name.
It was given to me
by someone who actually loves me,
which is better than I can say for you.
This is why I'm here.
I brought you this and I saved Roger
and now I'll be on my way.
It's the middle of the night.
I'll leave in the morning, then.
(ALETHIOMETER LID CLICKS OPEN)
(ALETHIOMETER LID CLICKS SHUT)
You can keep the alethiometer.
I don't need it.
You don't want it?
I didn't say that.
Hm.
I looked after this.
All the way from Jordan College!
Fought the Magisterium,
enlisted the witches, fought the bears,
all to bring it to you,
and you refuse it?
Call yourself a father?
I think that's rather the point.
I've never called myself a father.
(WHINES)
(DOOR CLANGS OPEN)
Have you intruded for a reason?
- The winds have changed direction.
- (DOOR CLOSES)
We should pick up speed now.
We'll be there by morning.
The Authority must be on our side.
I wouldn't be so arrogant
as to claim that.
Hopefully, we shall prove fast enough.
However fast we go,
Asriel will be waiting.
We have firepower and belief.
Two mighty weapons.
All he has is his own distorted arrogance.
And his work.
Work you don't want others to see, but...
...you really don't want
to see it yourself.
You want to see it?
I'm not frightened of it.
What did he do to you?
What power he still exerts!
You know nothing.
I knew you.
An ambitious young woman
with a good marriage,
well on her way to quite some position,
and then that man came along and you...
- ...melted in front of...
- I did not melt.
You don't even claim responsibility
for your child.
Hm.
I suppose you consider yourself
without sin.
No-one can claim to be without sin.
So what is your sin...
...I wonder?
Hm?
Lust?
Greed?
No.
It's envy.
You want what Asriel and I have.
A sureness of step, a conviction,
but you... you lack it.
I'm the best weapon you'll ever have.
Has it given you an answer?
An alethiometer gives you
the answer you need,
not necessarily the answer you desire.
- Sometimes it's more of a riddle than...
- What did it say?
The question I posed, very precisely,
is, "What did Grumman discover?"
What did the damn thing say?
It said...
...there's a knife in a tower
surrounded by angels.
That's what he has discovered.
And?
His son will lead you to it.
But Grumman never married,
never had a son.
So I may need to ask
another question, or...
A son?
You're sure it said a son?
For that part,
it gave me the levels of the baby,
the angel and the marionette symbols.
The answer was quite categorical.
(FOOTSTEPS APPROACH)
Tell me, sir,
does she have everything she needs?
- Hm?
- A brush for her teeth, for instance.
Does she have a toothbrush?
I wouldn't be overly concerned.
Now that Iofur's dead, there will be
an airship of soldiers on their way here.
But the Magisterium won't be
our only enemies for much longer.
You've found a bigger enemy?
The enemy.
And now that Iofur's guards are gone,
I'm free to go after it.
I'm afraid I won't be here
when the Magisterium arrives.
I'm going to ask you
to make sure that Lyra is safe.
After all this time,
you don't want me with you?
It's not that. I need you here.
I'm asking you to protect my daughter.
Will you say goodbye to her?
No. No, I have work.
It's the very least you could do.
(SIGHS)
PAN: We don't need Lord Asriel.
We'll leave in the morning at first light.
ROGER: Lyra.
- Are you there?
- I am.
And you're not coming in.
I'll come in, walk in backwards
and sit backwards.
Fine.
- Tell me if I'm going to hit anything.
- You aren't.
You can sit down there.
So what have you got?
What?
To say. Why are you in the bathroom?
Oh.
I just got spooked.
By what?
By your father. What's he doing here?
He looked at you really angrily,
and then he saw me
and he calmed down immediately.
He looked at me
like he was a wolf or something.
My father...
Can we... call him your father now?
He knows I know.
Didn't go so well?
Not really.
You know what I think?
Parents are more trouble
than they're worth.
That's why I never bothered
getting to know mine.
Sensible.
You know, I always liked it,
that we were the same.
Orphans.
So if you want...
...we can pretend we are.
(PAN SQUEAKS)
You shouldn't have let him go.
I... didn't know he was useful to us.
You wanted the letters.
He is.
He's important.
Tell me what to do.
I don't see why
I should get you to do anything.
You mess up.
You ask for help.
I give you Thomas,
and you mess up again.
Hang on...
And I... have to come myself.
Tell me...
...is there anything
that you can do alone?
Now, think...
...where this Will might be...
...what he might be doing.
The kid was a loner. My guess,
he's on the streets somewhere.
I'll look into it.
Get rid of the body.
Done.
And find the boy.
This is DI Walters to Control. Circulating
ops to all units in the Oxford area
for last name Parry, first name William.
15-year-old male, around five foot seven.
Likely on foot.
Reported missing person.
Any sightings,
please come to me direct.
Over.
RADIO: Copy, DI Walters.
This is Control.
On the lookout for last name Parry,
first name William.
15-year-old male...
(SPEECH FADES)
(BOTH SQUEAK)
(LYRA AND ROGER GIGGLE)
LYRA: Stop it!
He wasn't even surprised.
He wasn't even upset. He was just...
...annoyed at me.
It's probably not what he really thinks.
You sure about that?
You can look at the alethiometer.
Ask it how he really feels.
Does it know everything?
Does it know everything
that will happen to us?
I think so, but...
I think it will only tell me
what it wants me to know, so...
Then let's not use it.
So we just know what we know, I suppose.
I mean, I'm not like you.
I would never have chosen to leave Jordan.
I know.
But now here we both are,
halfway round the world.
And I'm here because of you.
And you're here because of me.
Cos we changed each other's lives.
I like the fact you changed my life.
Can't promise I won't stop changing it.
BOTH: Cheers.
(GIGGLING)
(WIND HOWLS)
(FOOTSTEPS APPROACH)
- Lyra.
- (PAN SQUEAKS)
Shh-shh-shh-shh. Don't be frightened.
Come.
ASRIEL: You once asked me
what Dust was.
The truth is, I don't know.
Why is the Magisterium so afraid of it?
They're afraid of it
because they think it is sin.
Actual physical sin.
Raining down from the sky,
settling on humanity
and infecting our souls with evil.
To be fair, it's a terrifying thought.
For the longest time,
the Magisterium completely ignored Dust.
But then it was discovered
that Dust only begins to settle
on humans going through puberty.
The connection was made to Adam and Eve...
...and they labelled Dust as original sin.
Original sin?
When did Eve's daemon settle?
When Eve ate the apple,
like the serpent told her to.
Well done.
And the serpent said,
"You shall not surely die,
"for the Authority doth know
that on that day that ye eat thereof,
"your eyes shall be opened,
"your daemons shall assume their true form
and ye shall be as..."
BOTH: "...gods, knowing good and..."
- "...evil."
- "...Dust."
You see?
They have been trying to convince us
for centuries that we are born guilty.
And that we have to spend a lifetime
atoning for the crime of eating an apple.
Is there any proof for this heinous stain,
this shame, this guilt?
No, not at all.
We are to take it on faith,
and on the word of the Authority.
But Dust...
Dust is an elementary particle
that we can record, measure, study.
We can take photograms of it.
And it has given them what they need -
a means by which to control, to oppress,
to frighten,
and to keep us where they want us -
on our knees.
That's what my mother
thinks she's doing...
...cutting away our daemons.
Preserving our sinless souls.
You should have seen them.
Those who had their daemons cut away.
They looked empty.
Did they try to cut you, Lyra?
She stopped them.
Your mother stopped them?
She didn't want to damage me.
Happy to damage others.
Is that a fact?
The thought of Pan being cut from me...
(PAN SCRATCHES)
(WHIMPERS QUIETLY)
I know.
The bond between human and daemon
is incredibly powerful.
Quite beautiful, really.
There's actually
an immense release of energy...
...when that link is severed.
What is the most important question
we can ask?
Where Dust comes from.
There you are.
- The photograms you took...
- The aurora.
You've seen Dust pouring
into this world from the aurora.
If light can cross that barrier
between the universes,
if Dust can,
if we can see that city up there
in the sky,
then we can build a bridge
and we can cross.
- Cross to multiple worlds?
- Why not?
Let's go to the source,
let's ask what Dust is.
Maybe we'll find out
that it's something else entirely.
Maybe we'll find out that
it is sin.
How do you like the sound of that?
I... I don't know.
What I do know is I've done my piece.
Lyra, what I can tell you is that Dust
is what makes the alethiometer work.
Did you know that?
I doubt the Magisterium know that.
It works through Dust?
I brought you the alethiometer
and now I just need to take Roger home.
Did the Master ever actually ask you
to bring it to me?
It's yours.
You were never sent to me at all.
But I am glad you came.
You don't come from nothing, Lyra.
You're the product
of something extraordinary.
Goodnight.
(FAINT WHIRRING)
(PHONE RINGS)
Anything?
No, nothing. But maybe
the police know something.
(LINE DISCONNECTS)
Fra Pavel said a tower.
It must be the Tower of the Angels.
The legends are true.
But if they are...
...then this knife...
The boy will lead us to it.
(FAINT LAUGHTER AND CHATTER)
(WHIRRING)
(FOOTSTEPS APPROACH)
(CLATTERING)
What...?
What's going on?
You're awake. Good.
Now, we have to move very quickly.
The Magisterium are on their way.
My father said they wouldn't get here.
- He's already gone.
- Where?!
Don't you worry.
I will get you somewhere safe.
Roger! Roger!
Where's Roger?
Tell me, Thorold! Where's Roger?
With Asriel.
What does he want with him?
Lyra... Lyra...
Energy.
Energy!
Lyra, I promised that I would protect you.
Thorold, he's going to cut him!
(WIND HOWLS)
Iorek!
Iorek, I need you!
Lyra! What is it?
Follow the footprints!
My father's got Roger. We need to go!
- Bears!
- You're calling the bears?
I have a feeling we'll be needing them.
Climb on.
We'll need to move fast!
(STELMARIA GROWLS)
What are we doing here?
When's Lyra joining us?
I told you, she's coming with Thorold.
She'll be here soon. Come.
(GUNSHOT)
(GOLDEN MONKEY GRUNTS)
Don't touch anything.
There'll be traps everywhere.
Get the guards out of here.
No sign of anyone or anything.
The guards have gone
to search the outside.
Plenty of people staying here, though.
Some sort of...
...encampment in the living area.
Any sense of where he might be?
Or what he's been...
...doing here?
Oh, Thorold, don't be ridiculous.
You won't hurt me.
I know you too well.
Plus, I'm unarmed.
He's gone up the mountain, hasn't he?
What's he trying to do?
His numbers suggest
some kind of energy release.
This is Dust... isn't it?
Thorold...
...tell me who's with him.
What's he trying to do with Dust?
Flood us all with sin and darkness?
I know you have no respect
for the Magisterium.
But in the name of the Authority,
he who shines above us
and lights the way,
tell me what you know.
(SIGHS) Thorold...
I should throw you to the wolves.
But I won't.
I'll tell them that Father MacPhail is
staying here to analyse what we've found.
And then I'll take the troops
to pursue Asriel, and then you will leave.
He's always been so reckless.
He's never treated any of us well.
You included.
(INHALES) Hm.
(LAUGHTER AND CHATTER NEARBY)
(DOOR OPENS AND CLOSES)
(POLICE RADIO CHATTER)
(DOOR CLOSES)
(WIND HOWLS)
(STELMARIA GROWLS)
Stay close!
What are you doing?
What's the surprise for Lyra?
(PANTS HEAVILY)
(WIND HOWLS)
(FAINT WHIRRING)
IOREK: They're heading for the mountain.
Bears, prepare yourself.
Bears spotted.
They're readying for an artillery attack.
Then open fire.
(YELLS)
- Prepare the fire-hurlers!
- Out of the way!
(EXPLOSIONS)
(SCREAMS)
Go! Go! Go!
(GUNFIRE)
(RAPID GUNFIRE)
(YELLS)
(MUFFLED EXPLOSIONS)
(WHOOSHING)
(EXPLOSION)
IOREK: (MUFFLED) Lyra!
Lyra!
Hurry, Lyra!
(DISTORTED) I'll get you to the mountain.
Isn't Lyra down there?
I think we should go and find her.
Come here!
- (GROWLS)
- (SQUEAKS)
ROGER: No!
What are you doing?!
- Get in!
- No!
Lord Asriel! No, stop!
No!
Lyra...
I cannot cross this bridge.
Thank you...
...King Iorek Byrnison.
...Lyra Silvertongue.
(KISSES)
Now go.
Quickly, Lyra.
(EXHALES)
(PANTS SHAKILY)
PAN: It's not far.
Just a few careful steps.
(GASPS)
ROGER: Lord Asriel, please!
I'm sorry that this is happening to you.
But in war, there are casualties.
And believe me when I tell you that
this is a war.
One that will free humanity for ever.
Lyra!
LYRA: I can't do this, Pan!
PAN: Come on, Lyra. You can.
LYRA: Just fly up
and see if you can see them.
We're nearly there.
They're just beyond the peak.
Asriel's put Roger and Salcilia in a cage.
They look like the ones at Bolvangar.
ROGER: No!
No!
(YELLS)
(SCREAMS)
(ROGER YELLS)
Please don't do this!
Lyra will never forgive you.
SALCILIA: Roger, I can't get out!
What's going to happen to us?
No... No.
(GRUNTS)
(ROGER SCREAMS)
No...
Roger, I don't want to leave you!
(RUMBLING)
(RUMBLING MUFFLED, SPEECH INAUDIBLE)
(BREATHES QUICKLY)
(STELMARIA GROWLS)
If you've come to stop me,
you're too late.
Too late to stop the experiment, yes,
but not too late to stop you.
Oh, I am pleased that you came, Marisa,
to see what I've done.
The Magisterium will never allow it.
Oh, you don't understand.
The Magisterium have no power any more.
Not once the world
sees the possibility of all this.
It is the end of the Magisterium.
After hundreds of years.
No more oppression.
No more abuse.
No more darkness...
...or suppression of knowledge.
You see that light?
That is the sun of another world.
Look.
Come.
Feel the warmth of it on your face.
(GASPS)
It's extraordinary.
(BOTH CHUCKLE)
ASRIEL: There is no stopping it now.
My war was never just
with the Magisterium.
There is a far more dangerous power
out there.
Marisa, come with me.
Work with me.
Help me fight this war
and take on the Authority.
Help me create a new Republic of Heaven.
What better place to make a new start?
A new start?
You and I. Together.
We could take this universe apart
and put it back together again.
Oh, no, no, no, no. No, we couldn't...
Lie about whatever you want.
Lie about the Oblation Board.
The Magisterium.
Lie about the girl.
But do not lie about your ambition...
...your work...
...or who you truly are.
You used to want to change the world.
Then leave the Magisterium.
Come with me, and we will change them all.
But our child is in this world.
And my place is with her.
That is not a lie.
You want that?
I want her with everything I have.
This is your journey,
not mine.
Goodbye, Asriel.
(FAINT CONVERSATION)
(POLICE RADIO CHATTER)
(GROANS)
LYRA: Roger...
(PAN SQUEAKS)
His face is warm.
But Salcilia's gone.
LYRA: I thought he wanted
the alethiometer.
I got it wrong.
I got it all... wrong.
PAN: We didn't mean this to happen.
But it did!
It did happen.
And I didn't get to say goodbye.
I didn't get to say I'm sorry.
And it's my fault.
It's all my fault.
I should never have brought you here.
What do I do, Roger?
Help me, please.
PAN: We need to find Dust.
We thought it was bad,
because grown-ups said so.
What if it isn't?
What if it needs protecting?
You're saying...
...we could...
...go and find Dust before he does?
Do you know what that means, Pan?
We'd be alone.
PAN: We've always been alone...
...apart from...
...Roger.
Do we just...
...leave him?
We've got to make sure they don't win.
We've got to go, Roger.
All right?
Me and Pan...
...are going to go into the skies
and we're going to search for Dust.
We will make sure
your death is not in vain.
Goodbye, Roger.
(CAT MEOWS)
(SIRENS WAIL)